<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Apache Allura</title><link href="//allura.apache.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//allura.apache.org/feeds/tag.feature.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>//allura.apache.org/</id><updated>2015-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Updated Icons, Cleaner Nav Bar</title><link href="//allura.apache.org/posts/2015-updated-icons.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:allura.apache.org,2015-10-28:posts/2015-updated-icons.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two big UI improvements have landed in Allura's master branch recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we've removed the icons for each tool (wiki, discussion, code, etc).  The icons looked dated, and cluttered
the project navigation bar.  They also presented challenges of what tool icon to use when a new tool was added.  So now
they are gone, and the project nav bar in particular looks much cleaner:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nav bar screenshot" src="//allura.apache.org/images/2015-updated-icons-nav.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, and even more exciting, is the use of Font Awesome icons throughout Allura.  They replace a small custom icon set
that had limited choices and was fixed-size.  Font Awesome has lots of choices and looks great on high resolution
screens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Icons screenshot" src="//allura.apache.org/images/2015-updated-icons.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy a nicer looking Allura!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
.pad-md img {
    margin: 2em;
}
&lt;/style&gt;</summary><category term="feature"></category></entry><entry><title>New Markdown Editor</title><link href="//allura.apache.org/posts/2015-markdown-editor.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:allura.apache.org,2015-07-29:posts/2015-markdown-editor.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Allura's markdown editor has been completely replaced.  Previously a simple textarea with limited assistance, it now runs
the &lt;a href="http://nextstepwebs.github.io/simplemde-markdown-editor/"&gt;SimpleMDE Markdown Editor&lt;/a&gt; and includes live syntax highlighting and
a helpful toolbar.  It will be included in the next release of Allura, or is available now by using the latest code from &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is a core part of Allura and is used in every text area, including tickets, wiki pages, commenting, etc.  Markdown
makes it easy to do simple formatting of your text, but not everyone is familiar with it.  The existing formatting help
and preview mode was helpful, but we wanted to do more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new editor's live syntax highlighting makes it really easy
to get an idea of what your text is going to look like and avoid formatting mistakes.  The preview mode is still there
to show you an exact rendering of the formatting.  And then the toolbar makes common formatting operations very easy.
It's a time saver and allows people new to Markdown to format their text without reading the comprehensive formatting
reference page.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="feature"></category></entry><entry><title>CORS support added to Allura</title><link href="//allura.apache.org/posts/2015-cors.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:allura.apache.org,2015-07-24:posts/2015-cors.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The latest Allura code now supports CORS http headers.  It will be included in the next release of Allura,
or is available now by using the latest code from &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Access_control_CORS"&gt;CORS headers&lt;/a&gt; allow JavaScript running on other sites
to access the Allura APIs.  By default, browser's Same Origin Policy would prevent that.  CORS is still secure, because Allura's
authenticate is in place.  APIs that require authorization still require it.  OAuth or OAuth tokens can be used,
cookies cannot be used - so nobody could be tricked into doing something accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enable this and allow more sites to integrate with Allura, see the &lt;code&gt;cors.*&lt;/code&gt; settings in your &lt;code&gt;development.ini&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="feature"></category></entry></feed>