<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Apache Allura</title><link href="//allura.apache.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//allura.apache.org/feeds/tag.feature.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>//allura.apache.org/</id><updated>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Two Factor Authentication</title><link href="//allura.apache.org/posts/2016-two-factor-auth.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:allura.apache.org,2016-09-17:posts/2016-two-factor-auth.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Support for enabling Two Factor Authentication(2FA) for users is now available in Allura's master branch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can enable 2FA by visiting their account preferences page and set it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Imgur" src="https://i.imgur.com/smRT9cL.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After clicking on the setup page, users will be asked for their password. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Imgur" src="https://i.imgur.com/u7HOXts.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users then install the Google Authenticator App for their smartphones. The links to install it can also be emailed to their accounts so that the link can be accessed from their phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Imgur" src="https://i.imgur.com/0YQjvVP.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users then scan the barcode and enter the time based six digit one time password generated by the mobile app in Allura. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After successfully setting up 2FA, users will be provided with recovery codes which can be used incase users get locked out of their account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Imgur" src="https://i.imgur.com/ulSxcaY.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An email is also sent to the user. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Imgur" src="https://i.imgur.com/chi6a3H.png?2" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can also modify their settings and view the recovery codes as well as disable 2FA from their account preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Imgur" src="https://i.imgur.com/BpDxbX3.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="feature"></category></entry><entry><title>New admin mode now available!</title><link href="//allura.apache.org/posts/2016-admin-toolbar.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:allura.apache.org,2016-01-14:posts/2016-admin-toolbar.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;When you use the same tools everyday, it is easy to evaluate how you spend most of your time. Even more apparent are the steps and processes that slow you down. Since all of us on the development team use these tools ourselves, we spent the end of the year discussing what processes have been slowing us down. Have you ever tried to rename a repo or give a user permission to moderate your project’s discussions? Did you even know you could do these things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exactly&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;As we realized where the hitch in the workflow was, we knew there was a more elegant solution. So we set out to build a new admin mode for all projects’ navigation bars. It provides easy access to add new tools to your project, as well as rename, reorder, configure, and delete any tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;To take this idea from concept to completion, we needed to modernize our frontend tooling. By leveraging Babel we were able to make use of the latest features of Javascript ES2015 and incorporate React and JSX into our workflow. We also wanted to ensure we maintained a clean, consistent style in our frontend code, so we started implementing ESLint. To tie it all together, we then chose Broccoli for our build system because of its incremental rebuilding and its incredibly fast compile times. By utilizing all these resources, we were able to create a new toolbar that approaches customization in a modern way and, as a byproduct, made future frontend endeavours more interesting to work on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Installing a New Tool&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="//allura.apache.org/images/toolbar/install.gif" class="drop-shadow" width="815" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Admin Toolbar is easy to find and use. There is a “Add New” link on every page, letting you install a new tool from anywhere.  With improved features like tooltips and real-time validation, the updated experience is more intuitive than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Tool Options&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="//allura.apache.org/images/toolbar/edit.gif" class="drop-shadow" width="815" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To change any tool settings, use the Lock/Unlock button on the right side of the bar.  This feature makes these options accessible when you need them and inconspicuous when you don’t.  And the gear icon opens up a context menu to manage your tools right from the interface, such as renaming, deleting, or setting specific options.  So you’re always only a few clicks away from all your tool settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Reordering Tools&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="//allura.apache.org/images/toolbar/reorder.gif" class="drop-shadow" width="815" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some key tools are anchored in place, but many tools are movable by dragging and dropping to the desired location.  Just the unlock button, and then drag and drop them into the order you want.  You can even customize the order within sub-menu dropdowns using this method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Grouping Similar Tools into Dropdowns&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="//allura.apache.org/images/toolbar/grouping.gif" class="drop-shadow" width="815"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have multiple tools of the same type, the Grouping Threshold option is available.  It determines if they will all fit in the navigation bar, or automatically be grouped into a dropdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go check it out!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="feature"></category></entry><entry><title>Updated Icons, Cleaner Nav Bar</title><link href="//allura.apache.org/posts/2015-updated-icons.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:allura.apache.org,2015-10-28:posts/2015-updated-icons.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two big UI improvements have landed in Allura's master branch recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we've removed the icons for each tool (wiki, discussion, code, etc).  The icons looked dated, and cluttered
the project navigation bar.  They also presented challenges of what tool icon to use when a new tool was added.  So now
they are gone, and the project nav bar in particular looks much cleaner:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nav bar screenshot" src="//allura.apache.org/images/2015-updated-icons-nav.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, and even more exciting, is the use of Font Awesome icons throughout Allura.  They replace a small custom icon set
that had limited choices and was fixed-size.  Font Awesome has lots of choices and looks great on high resolution
screens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Icons screenshot" src="//allura.apache.org/images/2015-updated-icons.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy a nicer looking Allura!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
.pad-md img {
    margin: 2em;
}
&lt;/style&gt;</summary><category term="feature"></category></entry><entry><title>New Markdown Editor</title><link href="//allura.apache.org/posts/2015-markdown-editor.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:allura.apache.org,2015-07-29:posts/2015-markdown-editor.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Allura's markdown editor has been completely replaced.  Previously a simple textarea with limited assistance, it now runs
the &lt;a href="http://nextstepwebs.github.io/simplemde-markdown-editor/"&gt;SimpleMDE Markdown Editor&lt;/a&gt; and includes live syntax highlighting and
a helpful toolbar.  It will be included in the next release of Allura, or is available now by using the latest code from &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is a core part of Allura and is used in every text area, including tickets, wiki pages, commenting, etc.  Markdown
makes it easy to do simple formatting of your text, but not everyone is familiar with it.  The existing formatting help
and preview mode was helpful, but we wanted to do more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new editor's live syntax highlighting makes it really easy
to get an idea of what your text is going to look like and avoid formatting mistakes.  The preview mode is still there
to show you an exact rendering of the formatting.  And then the toolbar makes common formatting operations very easy.
It's a time saver and allows people new to Markdown to format their text without reading the comprehensive formatting
reference page.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="feature"></category></entry><entry><title>CORS support added to Allura</title><link href="//allura.apache.org/posts/2015-cors.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:allura.apache.org,2015-07-24:posts/2015-cors.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The latest Allura code now supports CORS http headers.  It will be included in the next release of Allura,
or is available now by using the latest code from &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Access_control_CORS"&gt;CORS headers&lt;/a&gt; allow JavaScript running on other sites
to access the Allura APIs.  By default, browser's Same Origin Policy would prevent that.  CORS is still secure, because Allura's
authenticate is in place.  APIs that require authorization still require it.  OAuth or OAuth tokens can be used,
cookies cannot be used - so nobody could be tricked into doing something accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enable this and allow more sites to integrate with Allura, see the &lt;code&gt;cors.*&lt;/code&gt; settings in your &lt;code&gt;development.ini&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="feature"></category></entry></feed>